TAHIR SYED Page | 1

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

PROFILE:

I am SQA professional with 15+ years of progressive experience to deliver QA engineering solutions. Great experience in leading SQA teams with hands on experience of performing testing/analysis to develop QA methodologies across multiplatform solutions. Looking ahead for a new challenging position in SQA field to utilize my skills and deliver quality products in a timely manner.

CORE COMPETENCIES:

- Hands-on working experience in all phases of Software Quality Assurance to support web and client/server products on mobile (Android/iOS) and Windows platforms.
- Exceptional skills in in writing and developing all sort of test documentation including Test Cases, User Stories, Test Scenarios, Test Strategies, Test Plans, and Requirement Specifications.
- Knowledge of designing different test environments for manual and automated testing and executing test strategy for all kind of testing including Unit, Integration, Functional, System, Cross Browser, GUI, UAT, and Regression.
- Working experience of testing on real and virtual environments for Mobile Android/iOS and Windows platforms.
- Strong knowledge of SDLC methodology and its phases with experience in both Agile and Waterfall environments.
- Knowledge of Automation tools including Selenium WebDriver, Appium, Katalon Studio and ability to create scripts and design/setup automation environments using different tool.
- Excellent problem solving, troubleshooting and defect finding ability by using judgmental skills.
- Good experience of back-end testing using SQL Database and writing SQL DML queries.
- Working knowledge of Linux environment and Mac OS.
- Strong skills in dealing with stakeholders at all levels of project and working with product teams.
- Demonstrated managerial and lead experience for building QA teams by mentoring, motivating and performance evaluation of team members.

TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE & SKILLS:

Software Testing Tools:	Quality Center, Jira, Virtual Box, VMware, Fiddler, Jenkins, Zephyr, Test Rail		
Operating Systems:	Windows XP, 7, 8, 10, UNIX, Mac OS, Android, iOS, Linux		
Web Technologies:	XML, HTML, CSS, Java, Apache, GitHub, JMeter		
Mobile OS Technologies:	Android/iOS real and virtual devices, Android Studio, Device Anywhere, Perfecto Mobile, XCode		
Database Technologies:	RDBMS, SQL Server, Microsoft Access, pgAdmin		
Testing Documentation:	Test Cases, Test Plan, BRD, SOP, Design Documents		
Scripting/Automation Tools:	Katalon Studio, Selenium WebDriver, Appium, JUnit, TestNG		
Software Packages:	MS Office 365, MS Publisher, MS Project		

WORK EXPERIENCES:

Position Title	Duration	Company	Place
QA Test Engineer III	January 2020 – Present	Serco Inc	Herndon VA
Quality Assurance Lead/Manager	March 2014 – June 2019	ComScore Inc	Reston VA
Software Quality Assurance Engineer	July 2009 – March 2014	ComScore Inc	Reston VA
Senior Quality Assurance Analyst	August 2008 – July 2009	Aegis Mobile	Columbia MD
Technical Integration Manager	Mar 2007 – July 2008	Amazon.com	Seattle WA
Software Test Engineer	March 2006 – Feb 2007	Motorola Inc	Seattle, WA

TAHIR SYED Page | 2

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

DETAILED PROFFESIONAL WORK EXPERIENCES:

QA Test Engineer III Jan 2020 – Present Serco Inc, Herndon VA

Work Environment: CMS Healthcare Applications, Web UI and Database testing, API testing, Selenium, Microsoft SQL Server management Studio, VMware, Jira.

Job Responsibilities: & Achievements

- Lead test efforts for new features and monthly releases.
- Develop Test Plan, Test Scenarios, Test Cases and Test Data based on the requirements.
- Write, Validate and execute SQL scripts to validate test scenarios and test results.
- Running test validations at various levels including DB validation, logging validation, and UI validation.
- Perform both new functional and regression testing for Web UI changes.
- Identify, analyze and report issues for follow-up using JIRA.
- Perform both front-end UI testing and back-end API testing.
- Use Postman to create script for Web testing.
- Performing Gap Analysis on requirements and updating test cases, test suits and test runs in TestRail.
- Mentor junior QA team member on products and QA processes.

Quality Assurance Lead/Manager March 2014 – June 2019 ComScore Inc, Reston VA

Work Environment: Agile, Web, Mobile applications, Data collection and validation, API testing, Selenium, Microsoft SQL Server management Studio, VMware, Katalon Studio, Jira.

Job Responsibilities: & Achievements

- Lead multiple projects for end-to-end testing in Agile and Waterfall environments by working with product owners, development and test teams. Worked directly with business owners to perform user acceptance testing and assist in the production deployment activities.
- Successfully led test design and execution efforts by participating in Planning, Requirement gathering, Grooming, Scrum
 and Jira triage meetings. Added Jira Kanban board to Agile sprints to monitor continuous improvement and progress of
 project.
- Selection and setup of automation tools and created environment for Selenium WebDriver, Katalon Studio to transition regression and smoke test plans from manual to automation.
- Setup Jenkins jobs, created and assigned test cycles, review test results, created test metrics, oversee deployment of application to production, and resolve any post deployment production issues.
- Successfully managed QA team members to guide on product features, selection\training of new test tools, adding new test plans/test cases and automation of regression test plan.
- Participated in QA Audits by creating test reports using Jira and provided to third party QA process audits during Media Rating Council and Grant Thornton audits.

Software Quality Assurance Engineer - Mobile July 2009 – March 2014 ComScore Inc, Reston VA

Job Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked on Web and Mobile application testing and successfully added new test plans and test cases for multiple
 products to the system and implemented Automation scripts for web-based applications using TCB and Selenium.
- Performed hands-on application testing for new features on real and virtual devices by using different test tools like VMware, Virtual Box, Fiddler, Wireshark, DeviceAnyWhere and Android Studio, XCode.

TAHIR SYED Page | 3

Mobile: 571-428-7000 | Email: tahirsyyed@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/tahirs | https://tahirsyyed.github.io/

 Created Jira ticket for bugs found during testing and worked on defect resolution with developers to resolve issues by providing test logs and test environment details.

 Successfully achieved the delivery of products to apple and google play store which led my promotion to Manager role and lead the team.

Senior Quality Assurance Analyst August 2008 – July 2009 Aegis Mobile, Columbia MD

Job Environment: Mobile Content Validation, PMP, PACT, Verizon Wireless Campaign Administrator. MMA/CTIA, Crystal Reports, N-experience platform, XML, Java

Job Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked on mobile content validation and testing to analyze and implement Mobile Marketing Association (MMA)
 rules. This includes monitoring the Verizon Wireless Short Codes Services for validation and verifications of premier
 contents.
- Successfully implemented automation on the project by designing phone templates in XML and run the script on actual devices using Perfecto Mobile platform.

Technical Integration Manager/Analyst Mar 2007 – July 2008 Amazon.com Seattle WA

Job Environment: Kindle, RSS, XML, ATOM, E-publications, Win XP, Access, SQL Server, JIRA Bug tracking and management tool, Microsoft Share Points, MS Project.

Job Responsibilities & Achievements:

- Worked on integration of periodicals and newspapers for Amazon device Kindle by working with development and test teams to integrate third party contents received in XML, RSS Feeds, and atom format from local and international publishers.
- Successfully managed the project by delivering daily, weekly newspapers and magazine contents in electronic form to Kindle devices.

Software Test Engineer – Mobile/Web March 2006 – Feb 2007 Motorola INC. Seattle, WA

Job Environment: Functional Testing, ISO 9000, Java, XML, Rational DDTS, Test Central, TOAD, UNIX, Web logic, Apache Tomcat, RSS Feeds, WAP Deck.

Job Responsibilities Achievements:

- Worked on Screen3 project for Motorola to test the contents & delivery of Screen3 application on Motorola devices by recommended several enhancements to the process.
- Successfully executed several test cycles by implementing new test plan by adding 300+ test cases to it by using Test Central Platform

EDUCATION:

MS Management Information Systems Strayer University, Alexandria VA 2003-2005